Register of the Joseph Freeman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1915-1965
  - Joachim, Leo H., 1956 (Folder 3)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, 1937-1942. (Folder 4)
    Includes grant application material
  - Johns, Orrick, 1933-1936 (Folder 5)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1933-1935 (Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Oakley, 1958 (Folder 7)
  - Jones, Alfred, 1932 (Folder 8)
  - Jones, F. Elwyn, 1937 (Folder 9)
  - Jorge, Faustino E., 1937 (Folder 10)
  - Josephson, Matthew, 1925-1963 (Folder 11)
  - Kallen, Horace M., 1950 (Folder 12)
  - Kamman, Morris, 1938 (Folder 13)
  - Kandel, Aben, 1937-1938 (Folder 14)
  - Kantorowicz, Alfred, 1943-1944 (Folder 15)
  - Kapur, Jagdish, 1949-1964 (Folder 16)
  - Karachun, Anton, 1925 (Folder 17)
  - Katel, Helen, 1963 (Folder 18)
  - Katzenstein, Sigane, 1938-1939 (Folder 19)
  - Kaufman, Sidney, 1937-1951. (Folder 20)
  - Kay, Helen, 1934-1935 (Folder 21)
  - Keeler, Sally, 1937 (Folder 22)
  - Kelm, Karlton, 1933-1934 (Folder 23)
  - Kempton, Murray, 1953-1955 (Folder 24)
  - Kennedy, Jay Richard, 1952-1953 (Folder 25)
  - Kennell, Ruth, 1928 (Folder 26)
  - Kerillis, Henri de, 1951 (Folder 27)
  - Khosla, J. N., 1961 (Folder 28)
  - Kiesler, Frederick and Steffi, 1938-1964 (Folder 29)
  - Kimball, Alice Mary, 1925-1935 (Folder 30)
  - King, Carol, 1933 (Folder 31)
  - King, Nettie, 1943 (Folder 32)
  - King-Farlow, John, 1951. (Folder 33)
    Includes poems by King-Farlow
  - Kirchwey, Freda, 1925-1955 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1931 (Folder 2)
  - Klein, Herbert, 1934 (Folder 3)
  - Klein, Marvin, 1933 (Folder 4)
  - Kline, Herbert, 1935-1948. (Folder 5)
    Includes letter by another; SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/"The Triumph of Life," 1947 and SUBJECT FILE/Theater/New Theatre League
  - Klopfer, Marian and Donald, 1935-1938 (Folder 6)
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1947 (Folder 7)
  - Koch, Lucien, 1934-1935 (Folder 8)
  - Kocher, Esther, 1934 (Folder 9)
  - Kolmanoff, A., undated (Folder 10)
  - Komarovsky, Mirra and Marcus Heyman, 1928-1964 (Folder 11)
  - Komorowski, Conrad, 1932-1935 (Folder 12)
  - Kooperman, Joseph, 1936-1938 (Folder 13)
  - Korchien, Jules E. and Lillian, 1931-1935 (Folder 14)
  - Korovay, Michael, 1932 (Folder 15)
  - Kovarowsky, V., 1952 (Folder 16)
  - Kraemer, Chris, 1938-1939. (Folder 17)
    SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/ Agriculture
  - Kramberg, Ruth, 1932 (Folder 18)
  - Kropotkin, Alexandra, 1955-1956 (Folder 19)
  - Kruse, Gussie, 1928 (Folder 20)
  - Kuh, Frederick, 1932-1946 (Folder 21)
  - Kuhn, Irene, 1945 (Folder 22)
  - Kunitz, Jack, 1934 (Folder 23)
  - Kunitz, Stanley, 1963 (Folder 24)
  - Lall, Arthur, 1951 (Folder 25)
  - Lamb, Beatrice Pitney, 1946-1949. (Folder 26)
  - Lamont, Corliss, 1933-1965 (Folder 27)
  - Landi, Elissa, 1937-1948. (Folder 28)
    Includes an obituary, and a poem by Landi relating to Ernst Toller
  - Landi, Charles Z. (Pi), 1948-1950 (Folder 29)
  - Lang, Joseph (Folder 30)
  - Langhammer, John, 1941 (Folder 31)
  - Lapin, K., 1938 (Folder 32)
  - Larkin, Margaret, 1925 (Folder 33)
  - Lash, Joseph, 1953 (Folder 34)
  - Laski, Harold, 1937-1943. (Folder 35)
    Includes a review of American Testament and correspondence with another
  - Lasky, Melvin, 1952-1963. (Folder 36)
    Includes a letter to another
  - Lastfogel, Abe, 1945 (Folder 37)
  - Latin Quarterly, 1934 (Folder 38)
  - Latour, Onya, 1935 (Folder 39)
  - Lawrence, Seymour (Atlantic Monthly), 1959-1961 (Folder 40)
  - Lawson, John Howard, 1937-1965 (Folder 41)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1925 (Folder 42)
  - Leavitt, Julian, 1929 (Folder 43)
  - Lee, Russell W., 1935?-1937 (Folder 44)
  - Left Front, 1933-1934 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Leider, William, 1938 (Folder 2)
  - Leon, Carlos, 1929 (Folder 3)
  - Lerner, Max, 1936-1959 (Folder 4)
  - Levine, Harry, 1940-1944 (Folder 5)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1963 (Folder 6)
  - Levitas, Mitchel, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Lewin, Al, 1935 (Folder 8)
  - Lewis, Albert, 1934 (Folder 9)
  - Lewis, James Franklin, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - Leyda, Jay, 1933-1956. (Folder 11)
    Includes writings by Leyda
  - Liberator, 1921-1923 (Folder 12)
  - Liberman, Simon, 1945 (Folder 13)
  - Lippman, Sophie, 1945 (Folder 14)
  - Lipsitz, Louis, 1958 (Folder 15)
  - Lipton, Lawrence, 1935-1945 (Folder 16)
  - Littauer, Sebastian, 1933 (Folder 17)
  - Litvinov, Ivy, 1928-1962. (Folder 18)
    Includes letters by Tanya Litvinov; SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Litvinov, Ivy
  - Living Age, 1940 (Folder 19)
  - Loeb, Harold and Vera, 1949-1953 (Folder 20)
  - Lombardo Toledano, Vicente, 1937-1940 (Folder 21)
  - Lord, Frederic, 1937. (Folder 22)
    Includes printed matter and letter to another
  - Lore, Ludwig, 1922 (Folder 23)
  - Loveman, Sam, 1931-1962 (Folder 24)
  - Lovett, Robert Morss, 1938. (Folder 25)
    Includes an obituary
  - Loving, Pierre, 1921?-1935 (Folder 26)
  - Lozowick, Louis, 1936 (Folder 27)
  - Lvovitch, Lavy Moishe, 1921-1952 (Folder 28)
  - Lyons, Eugene, 1930-1940 (Folder 29)
  - Lyons, Leonard, 1952-1961 (Folder 30)
  - McCabe, Robert, 1962 (Folder 31)
  - McCaffrey, John, 1946-1952. (Folder 32)
  - McCarthy, Mary, 1953. (Folder 33)
    Includes prospectus for Critic
  - Macdonald, Dwight, 1952 (Folder 34)
  - McKay, Claude, 1921-1922 (Folder 35)
  - McKenzie, Cameron (Friday), 1940 (Folder 36)
  - McKenna, Kasey, 1933-1934 (Folder 37)
  - McKeon, Richard, 1920-1952 (Folder 38)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1936-1940 (Folder 39)
  - Macleod, Norman, 1930 (Folder 40)
    Includes poems by Macleod
  - McLernon, Frances, 1938-1939 (Folder 41)
  - Maeder, Ruth K., 1954 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Malisoff, William M., 1921 (Folder 2)
  - Maltz, Albert, 1935-1947 (Folder 3)
  - Maltz, Edward, 1931-1943 (Folder 4)
  - Mancisidor, Raimundo, 1937. (Folder 5)
    Includes writings by Mancisidor
  - Mandel, George, 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Mann, Klaus (Decision), 1941 (Folder 7)
  - Marinello, Juan, 1937 (Folder 8)
  - Markel, Lael, 1950-1952 (Folder 9)
  - Marshall, John, 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Marshall, Lenore G., 1934-1935 (Folder 11)
  - Marshall, Thurgood, 1949. (Folder 12)
    Includes printed article by Marshall
  - Martini, Laura, 1953 (Folder 13)
  - Marvin, Mark, 1936-1938 (Folder 14)
  - Massing, Paul and Hede, 1934-1956 (Folder 15)
  - Matthews, Maude, 1939-1944 (Folder 16)
  - Matthews, Stanley, 1938 (Folder 17)
  - Mavor, Geraldine, 1939?-1940 (Folder 18)
  - Meldrum, Peggie, 1921-1923 (Folder 19)
  - Mellquist, Jerome, 1938 (Folder 20)
  - Melville, Nina, 1963-1964 (Folder 21)
  - Mendelevsky, M., 1925 (Folder 22)
  - Merrick, Helen Hynson, 1937-1938 (Folder 23)
  - Merrill, Roberta, 1954-1956. (Folder 24)
    Includes poems by Merrill
  - Messinger, E. F. (Ferrand) and Carmen, 1935-1946 (Folder 25)
  - Meyer, Monroe, 1924-1938. (Folder 26)
    Includes correspondence with others
  - Meyer, Pearl, 1939-1943 (Folder 27)
  - Meyerhold, Vsevold, 1927-1933 (Folder 28)
  - Michel, Concha, 1932-1935. (Folder 29)
    Includes songs and miscellany
  - Millan, Verna Carleton, 1943 (Folder 30)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1937-1950. (Folder 31)
    Includes obituary
  - Miller, Fred R., 1948-1955. (Folder 32)
    Includes poems by Miller
  - Minor, Robert, 1923-1942 (Folder 33)
  - Modern Age Books, Inc., 1938-1942 (Folder 34)
  - Modotti, Ben, undated (Folder 35)
  - Modotti, Tina, 1929 (Folder 36)
  - Moldawer, Mac, 1950 (Folder 37)
  - Mondrian, Piet, 1942 (Folder 38)
  - Moore, Harry Thornton, 1938 (Folder 39)
  - Morgan, Peter, 1934. (Folder 40)
    Includes writing by Morgan
  - Moriarty, Martin, 1934 (Folder 41)
  - Moult, Thomas, 1921 (Folder 42)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1934 (Folder 43)
  - Murphy, Jack T. and Molly, 1931-1965. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Includes writing by Jack Murphy
  - Murray, John, 1937 (Folder 2)
  - Mussilawin, Raya, 1947-1964 (Folder 3)
  - Naft, Stephen, 1925-1941 (Folder 4)
  - Nathan, Otto, 1950 (Folder 5)
  - Nation, 1931-1964. (Folder 6)
    Includes letters by Bruce Bliven, King Gordon, Carey McWilliams, and others; SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE FILE/Kirchwey, Freda and Minor, Robert
  - Nearing, Scott, 1924-1958. (Folder 7)
    SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/ Dollar Diplomacy, 1925
  - Negri, Ramon de, 1930 (Folder 8)
  - Neininger, Jeannie, 1965 (Folder 9)
  - Nemetz, K. C., 1951 (Folder 10)
  - Neumann, Emanuel, 1940-1958 (Folder 11)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1953-1954 (Folder 12)
  - New Quarterly (Jay du Von), 1934 (Folder 13)
  - New Republic, 1933-1945. (Folder 14)
    Includes correspondence with Bruce Bliven, Malcolm Cowley and others
  - New School for Social Research, 1958 (Folder 15)
  - Newberry Library
    Includes correspondence with Stanley Pargellis and others
    - 1949-1953 (Folder 16)
    - 1954-1965 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Newhouse, Edward, 1936-1938 (Folder 2)
  - Newton, Caroline, 1926-1939 (Folder 3)
  - Nomad, Max (Max Nacht), 1931-1958 (Folder 4)
  - Norman, Dorothy and Edward, 1938-1958 (Folder 5)
  - Novak, Alexander, undated (Folder 6)
  - Nurenberg, Thelma, 1931 (Folder 7)
  - Oak, Liston, 1933-1941 (Folder 8)
  - O'Callaghan, May, 1926-1933 (Folder 9)
  - Odets, Clifford, 1936-1937 (Folder 10)
  - O'Dwyer, Paul, 1943-1953 (Folder 11)
  - O'Dwyer, William, 1940-1953. (Folder 12)
    Includes a poem by Freeman and notes by Freeman and another
  - Olgin, Moissaye, 1932 (Folder 13)
  - Olson, Martha, 1953-1955 (Folder 14)
  - O'Mally, Jack, 1960-1964 (Folder 15)
  - Orozco, Jose Clemente, 1936-1949 (Folder 16)
  - Osborn, Reuben, 1936-1939 (Folder 17)
  - Oumansky, Constantin, 1933-1939 (Folder 18)
  - Overdick, Mrs., 1944-1945 (Folder 19)
  - Owen, Billie, 1922-1930 (Folder 20-21)
  - Paalen, Wolfgang, 1949 (Folder 22)
  - Page, George Nelson, 1931-1932 (Folder 23)
  - Page, Helen, 1947 (Folder 24)
  - Page, Myra, 1931 (Folder 25)
  - Parker, Dorothy, 1938 (Folder 26)
  - Parker, William Riley, 1941 (Folder 27)
  - Parry, Albert, 1933. (Folder 28)
    Includes writing by Parry
  - Partisan Review, 1934-1951. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Alan Calmer, Fred Dupee, and Philip Rahv, Delmore Schwartz, a report by Freeman, and a memorandum by Granville Hicks
  - Paschal, Marian, 1944 (Folder 2)
  - Pass, Joseph, 1934-1936 (Folder 3)
  - Passloff, Dotty, 1944 (Folder 4)
  - Pavlov, I., 1928-1930 (Folder 5)
  - Pearce, C. A., 1933-1944 (Folder 6)
  - Pearl, Diana, 1929 (Folder 7)
  - Pearlman, Meyer, 1940-1949 (Folder 8)
  - Pehn, Mura, 1939 (Folder 9)
  - Pentland, Lord, 1950 (Folder 10)
  - Percival, Willa, 1957 (Folder 11)
  - Peters, Paul, 1938 (Folder 12)
  - Pilnyak, Boris, 1931-1934. (Folder 13)
    Includes correspondence with others; SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Pilynak, Boris and SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Ghost-writing projects/Pilynak, Boris
  - Pizits [Neuman], Sylvia, 1954-1958 (Folder 14)
  - Plenn, Abel, 1933-1937 (Folder 15)
  - Pope, Arthur Upham, circa 1943. (Folder 16)
    Includes a memorandum
  - Popini, Alexander, 1943 (Folder 17)
  - Poster, William, 1946. (Folder 18)
    Includes writings by Poster
  - Poyntz, Juliet Stuart, 1932 (Folder 19)
  - Pozner, Vladimir, 1938-1940 (Folder 20)
  - Pressly, Eugene D., 1932 (Folder 21)
  - Preston, John Hyde, 1938 (Folder 22)
  - Pruette, Lorine, undated (Folder 23)
  - Quirt, Walter, 1937-1939 (Folder 24)
  - Radamsky, Sergei, 1933-1956. (Folder 25)
    Includes memorandum by Radamsky and printed matter
  - Ramos Pedruezza, Rafael, 1934-1935. (Folder 26)
    Includes writing by Ramos Pedruezza
  - Ramsey, David (Hymen Rosen) and Selma [Freeman], 1924-1965 (Folder 27-30)
  - Rantz, Berta, 1945-1947 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Raphaelson, Joel, 1950 (Folder 2)
  - Ray, Nicholas, 1938 (Folder 3)
  - Rebold, Elizabeth, undated (Folder 4)
  - Reed, Alma, 1936-1965 (Folder 5)
  - Reik, Theodore, 1940-1944 (Folder 6)
  - Reisky, Clara, 1938 (Folder 7)
  - Ribard, Andre, 1938 (Folder 8)
  - Rice, Elmer and Hazel, 1932-1947 (Folder 9)
  - Richter, Hans, 1942-1961 (Folder 10)
  - Ridge, Lola, undated (Folder 11)
    Includes poem by Ridge
  - River, Les, 1931-1939 (Folder 12)
  - Rivera, Diego, (unsent), 1930 (Folder 13)
  - Rivlin, Benjamin, 1942 (Folder 14)
  - Robb, Dorothy, 1924-1925 (Folder 15)
  - Robin, Frederick, 1948-1951 (Folder 16)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton, 1920-1957 (Folder 17)
  - Robinson, Ione, 1929-1964. (Folder 18-20)
  - Robinson, Selma, 1917-1961. (Folder 21)
    Includes poems by Lorin Robinson
  - Rocke, Gilbert, 1933 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Rodgers, Frank, 1949-1950 (Folder 2)
  - Rodker, John, 1921-1925 (Folder 3)
  - Rodriguez, Carlos Rafael, 1937 (Folder 4)
  - Roeder, Ralph, 1956 (Folder 5)
  - Roger, Ed, 1933-1934. (Folder 6)
    Includes writings by Roger
  - Rogers, Maria, 1951-1953 (Folder 7)
  - Rogge, O. John, 1959-1963. (Folder 8)
    Includes writing by Rogge
  - Rohman, Richard, 1920-1935 (Folder 9)
  - Rolfe, Edwin and Mary, 1925-1954. (Folder 10)
    Includes writings by Rolfe
  - Rolland, Romain, 1932 (Folder 11)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1954 (Folder 12)
  - Root, E. Merrill, 1925-1926 (Folder 13)
  - Rorty, James and Winifred, 1932-1944 (Folder 14)
  - Rosen, Hymen and Selma [Freeman].
    SEE: Ramsey, David and Selma
  - Rosenberg, Nathan, 1939 (Folder 15)
  - Rosenfeld, Henry L., Jr., 1933-1936 (Folder 16)
  - Ross, David, 1946-1951 (Folder 17)
  - Ross, Irwin, 1947-1958 (Folder 18)
  - Rossides, Zenon, 1962 (Folder 19)
  - Roth, Samuel, 1921-1927 (Folder 20)
  - Roumain, Jacques, 1936 (Folder 21)
  - Rovere, Richard, 1948-1950 (Folder 22)
  - Rovinsky, Hyman, 1921 (Folder 23)
  - Roy, Constance, 1943-1944 (Folder 24)
  - Royce, Pauline, 1931 (Folder 25)
  - Rubin, Jessie, 1938-1957 (Folder 26)
  - Rubin, Sylvia, 1935 (Folder 27)
  - Ruellan, Andree, 1935 (Folder 28)
  - Ruiz, Ramon Eduardo, 1941 (Folder 29)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1930-1943 (Folder 30)
  - Ruml, Beardsley, 1945 (Folder 31)
  - Ruthenberg, Charles E., 1925 (Folder 32)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1956 (Folder 33)
  - Sano, Seki, 1939 (Folder 34)
  - Saturday Review (Henry Seidel Canby), 1941-1943 (Folder 35)
  - Saxon, Olin Glenn, 1949 (Folder 36)
  - Schaap, Al, 1926 (Folder 37)
  - Schack, Bill, 1920-1957 (Folder 38)
  - Schapiro, Meyer [Mike], 1932-1933 (Folder 39)
  - Schillinger, Frances [Singer], 1938-1953 (Folder 40)
    Includes printed matter and writings by Joseph Schillinger
  - Schmer, Henry, 1956 (Folder 41)
  - Schneider, Isidor, 1934-1937. (Folder 42)
    Includes letters to another
  - Schrier, Sophie, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Schulkind, Adelaide, (Adelaide Schulkind Frank), 1943 (Folder 2)
  - Schulte, Arthur and Luise, 1951-1955 (Folder 3)
  - Schuyler, Mary, undated (Folder 4)
  - Schwartz, Alice H., 1932-1933 (Folder 5)
  - Schwartz, Daniel, 1938-1939 (Folder 6)
  - Schwartz, Harry, 1932 (Folder 7)
  - Schwarzbart, Elias, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Scognamillo, Fabian, 1945-1946 (Folder 9)
  - Scott, Mrs. Chris G., 1925 (Folder 10)
  - Scott, John, 1942-1965 (Folder 11)
  - Seaver, Edwin, 1923-1944 (Folder 12)
  - Segal, Paul, 1922 (Folder 13)
  - Seldes, Gilbert, 1921?-1923 (Folder 14)
  - Seligmann, Kurt, 1943 (Folder 15)
  - Selva, Solomon de la, 1937-1939. (Folder 16)
    Includes a memorandum relating to the immigration of Jews into Mexico
  - Shachtman, Max, 1924. (Folder 17)
    Includes press release
  - Shapiro, Olga J., 1931 (Folder 18)
  - Sheean, Mrs. V., 1936 (Folder 19)
  - Shelley, Edwin, 1935-1947 (Folder 20)
  - Shelley, Gilbert, 1936 (Folder 21)
  - Shelley, Jean (Eugenia), 1935-1937. (Folder 22)
    Includes poem by Shelley
  - Shelley, Louis, 1920-1938 (Folder 23)
  - Shelley, Robert and Jessie, 1917-1943. (Folder 24-26)
    Includes letter to Earl Browder by Robert Shelley relating to Freeman
  - Shelley, Sidney, 1938 (Folder 27)
  - Shepard, Odell, 1943 (Folder 28)
  - Shick, Edith, 1944-1946 (Folder 29)
  - Shields, Art, 1928 (Folder 30)
  - Shipman, Sam, 1934 (Folder 31)
  - Siegel, Eli, 1923-1958. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Includes writings by Siegel
  - Siegel, R. Lawrence, 1950-1954 (Folder 2)
  - Sills, Sibyl, 1938 (Folder 3)
  - Simon, Eva, 1938-1939 (Folder 4)
  - Simon and Schuster (Quincy Howe, M. Lincoln Schuster, and Henry Simon), 1930-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Simonson, Lee, undated (Folder 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1928-1941. (Folder 7)
    Includes material relating to Sergei Eisenstein
  - Singer, Herman, 1951-1961 (Folder 8)
  - Siporin, Mitchell, 1932-1934 (Folder 9)
  - Siquieros, David Alfaro, 1932-1935. (Folder 10)
    Includes an outline and biographical note prepared by Freeman?
  - Siskind, Aaron, 1953 (Folder 11)
  - Sitkin, Hazel, 1949-1954 (Folder 12)
  - Skladman, Jeannette, 1931-1934 (Folder 13)
  - Skvirsky, B. E., 1931-1932 (Folder 14)
  - Sloan, Mary Bell, 1935 (Folder 15)
  - Slochower, Harry, 1935-1956. (Folder 16)
    Includes printed matter and writing by Slochower
  - Slocum, Louis, 1938 (Folder 17)
  - Smedley, Agnes, 1934-1943 (Folder 18)
  - Smirnov, Victor, 1938-1939. (Folder 19)
    Includes writings by Smirnov
  - Smith, Bernard, 1932-1938 (Folder 20)
  - Smith, Betty, 1953 (Folder 21)
  - Smith, Charles, 1933 (Folder 22)
  - Smith, Harry, 1953 (Folder 23)
  - Smith, Jessica, 1925-1962 (Folder 24)
  - Smith, William and Marion [Freeman][Hammett], 1919-1963 (Folder 25-26)
  - Snyder, David, 1947-1961 (Folder 27)
  - Snyder, Gretchen, 1954 (Folder 28)
  - Sobel, Bernard, 1944-1955 (Folder 29)
  - Solasko, Bella, 1930-1935 (Folder 30)
  - Solomon, Flo, 1943 (Folder 31)
  - Spicer, Julia, 1938 (Folder 32)
  - Spingold, Nate B., 1943-1947 (Folder 33)
  - Standard Oil Company, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Starobin, Joseph R., 1957-1962 (Folder 2)
  - Stavis, Barrie, 1939 (Folder 3)
  - Stead, Christine and William, 1936-1938 (Folder 4)
  - Steele, John S., 1921-1935 (Folder 5)
  - Steffens, Lincoln, 1933-1937. (Folder 6)
    Includes letter by Steffens to Whittaker Chambers
  - Steffens, Pete, 1931-1949 (Folder 7)
  - Steinbeck, John, 1940 (Folder 8)
  - Steinberg, Milton, 1946-1948 (Folder 9)
  - Steiner, Ralph, undated (Folder 10)
  - Steinhardt, Jacinto, 1925-1934 (Folder 11)
  - Stern, Bernhard J., 1931-1939 (Folder 12)
  - Stevens, Florence B., 1937-1938 (Folder 13)
  - Stevens, Virginia, 1939 (Folder 14)
  - Stevenson, Philip, 1935 (Folder 15)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1936-1963 (Folder 16)
  - Stout, Miner Kennedy, 1919 (Folder 17)
  - Stout, Rex, 1942 (Folder 18)
  - Stout, Ruth, 1925-1935? (Folder 19)
  - Strachey, John, 1936-1938 (Folder 20)
  - Strand, Paul, 1935-1938 (Folder 21)
  - Strunsky, Sheba, 1931 (Folder 22)
  - Struther, Jan, 1944-1945 (Folder 23)
  - Studio Theatre, 1941 (Folder 24)
  - Sugihara, Ina, 1943 (Folder 25)
  - Sunderam, Chinni, 1951-1962 (Folder 26)
  - Sweeney, Frances, 1943-1944. (Folder 27)
    Includes printed matter and writings by Sweeney
  - Swift, O. P., undated (Folder 28)
  - Sykes, Gerald and Buffie, 1951-1952 (Folder 29)
  - Taffel, Edgar, 1932-1933 (Folder 30)
  - Taggard, Genevieve, 1924-1935 (Folder 31)
  - Talmadge, Irving DeWitt, 1941 (Folder 32)
  - Tannenbaum, Samuel A., 1939-1940 (Folder 33)
  - Tao, H. C., 1937 (Folder 34)
  - Tarail, Mark, 1932-1933 (Folder 35)
  - Tartar, Eve, 1953 (Folder 36)
  - Taub, Allan, 1938 (Folder 37)
  - Theatre Arts Books, 1949-1950 (Folder 38)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1942-1951 (Folder 39)
  - Thurman, Wallace, undated (Folder 40)
  - Todes, Charlotte, 1933-1935 (Folder 41)
  - Tombacher, Juliette, 1920 (Folder 42)
  - Tomorrow (Katherine Woods and others), 1943-1952 (Folder 43)
  - Toogood, Granville, 1941-1943 (Folder 44)
  - Toor, Frances (Paca), 1929-1935 (Folder 45)
  - Topehevsky, Morris, 1935 (Folder 46)
  - Touby, Louis, 1933-1934. (Folder 47)
  - Town Hall, Inc., 1938-1939 (Folder 48)
  - Trachtenberg, Alexander, 1925-1935 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Travers, Jean, 1934-1938 (Folder 2)
  - Tsiang, H. T., 1938-1941 (Folder 3)
  - Tucker, Peggy, 1924-1934 (Folder 4)
  - Unell [Thine], Richard, 1935 (Folder 5)
  - United States. Office of War Information, 1945 (Folder 6)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1939-1964 (Folder 7)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1922-1923 (Folder 8)
  - Valdes-Rodriguez, Jose, 1933 (Folder 9)
  - Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1923 (Folder 10)
  - Van Doren, Carl, 1920-1938 (Folder 11)
  - Van Dyke, Willard, 1933-1934 (Folder 12)
  - Van Kleeck, Mary, 1931 (Folder 13)
  - Vanguard Press, 1932-1937 (Folder 14)
  - Varese, Edgar, 1943 (Folder 15)
  - Verlinsky, Vladimir, 1937 (Folder 16)
  - Virduzzo, Antonio, 1962 (Folder 17)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review (Stringfellow Barr), 1930-1948 (Folder 18)
  - Vivas, Eliseo, 1925 (Folder 19)
  - Vivo, Jorge, 1937 (Folder 20)
  - Vlavianos, Basil, 1962. (Folder 21)
    Includes writing by Vlavianos
  - Von Wiegand, Charmion. Including letters to others and writing by von Wiegand
    - Undated (Folder 22)
    - 1919-1948 (Folder 23-26)
    - 1949-1964 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Von Wiegand, Inez, 1935-1957 (Folder 2)
  - Von Wiegand, Karl, 1927-1962 (Folder 3-5)
  - Von Wiegand, Norma Lee, undated (Folder 6)
  - Von Wiegand, Norman, 1945-1951 (Folder 7)
  - Voros, Sandor, 1958-1961 (Folder 8)
  - Vorse, Mary Heaton, 1950 (Folder 9)
  - Waldman, Mark, 1934 (Folder 10)
  - Waldman, Nat, 1943 (Folder 11)
  - Walker, Charles, 1934 (Folder 12)
  - Walpin, Bennie, 1942 (Folder 13)
  - Walrond, Eric, 1924-1925 (Folder 14)
  - Walser, Frank, 1939 (Folder 15)
  - Walton, Marcia, 1944 (Folder 16)
  - Wardle, Dely Monteser, 1949 (Folder 17)
  - Warner, Norman, 1932-1934 (Folder 18)
  - Weaver, Raymond M., 1918-1920 (Folder 19)
  - Wechsler, James, 1937-1956 (Folder 20)
  - Wei, Ellin, 1950 (Folder 21)
  - Weil, Felix, 1944 (Folder 22)
  - Weil, Louis, 1915-1920 (Folder 23)
  - Weinberg, Herman, 1962-1964 (Folder 24)
  - Weinzweig, Irving, 1921-1930 (Folder 25)
  - Weinzweig, Mac (Mac Windsor), 1920-1930. (Folder 26)
    Includes course outline
  - Wertham, Frederick and Florence, 1939-1962. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    Includes printed matter and writings by Frederick Wertham
  - Weston, Edward, undated (Folder 2)
  - White, Ruth, undated (Folder 3)
  - Whitehead, John F., 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Widen, Ruth and Lew Ney, 1934 (Folder 5)
  - Willen, Paul, 1951-1956 (Folder 6)
  - Willen, Pearl and Joseph, 1946-1964 (Folder 7)
  - William Morris Agency, 1940 (Folder 8)
  - Williams, Albert Rhys and Lucita, 1933-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Williams, Annie, and Bill Feinberg, 1938-1964 (Folder 10)
  - Williams, Annie Laurie, 1942-1944 (Folder 11)
  - Williams, Marie, undated (Folder 12)
  - Williams, Oscar, 1920-1955. (Folder 13)
    Includes writings by Williams
  - Williams, Spencer, 1941-1947 (Folder 14)
  - Willner, George and Tiba, 1932-1963. (Folder 15)
    SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/ New Masses/Correspondence
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1934-1947 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, Hugh and Muriel, 1953-1954 (Folder 2)
  - Wing, Willis, 1940 (Folder 3)
  - Winner, Percy and Helen, 1920-1934 (Folder 4)
  - Winter, Ella, 1928-1963. (Folder 5-8)
  - Wise, Howard, 1963 (Folder 9)
  - Wittfogel, Esther, 1943 (Folder 10)
  - Wittfogel, Olga L., 1942. (Folder 11)
    Includes writings by Karl Wittfogel
  - Wolf, Robert L., 1925-1926 (Folder 12)
  - Wolfe, Bertram, 1925-1963 (Folder 13)
  - Wolfe, Ella, 1925-1963 (Folder 14)
  - Wolfe, Thomas, 1955 (Folder 15)
  - Wolfe, W. Beran, 1934 (Folder 16)
  - Wolff, Eleanor, 1963-1964 (Folder 17)
  - Wolpe, Stefan, 1939 (Folder 18)
  - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott and Sara Bard Field, 1928-1933 (Folder 19)
  - Wood, Clement, 1921 (Folder 20)
  - Wood, Robert, 1938-1939 (Folder 21)
  - Woods, Katherine, 1945-1947 (Folder 22)
  - Woolf, Helene, 1935 (Folder 23)
  - Woolf, Paul, undated (Folder 24)
  - Workers Defense League, 1943 (Folder 25)
  - Wright, Richard, 1941 (Folder 26)
  - The Writer (A. S. Burack), 1943 (Folder 27)
  - Wrong, Dennis, 1956. (Folder 28)
    Includes writing by Wrong
  - Wylie, Ted, 1936 (Folder 29)
  - Wynne, Connie, undated (Folder 30)
  - Yezierska, Anzia, 1950 (Folder 31)
  - Young, Art, 1923-1935 (Folder 32)
  - Young, Deene, 1932-1938 (Folder 33)
  - Zapata, Robert, 1953 (Folder 34)
  - Zeisler, Ernest B., 1952-1953 (Folder 35)